Okay, let's go through our converting between types exercise.
So converting between strings and numbers, I can make a new string like this, right?
Or if I wanted to pass a number into, if I wanted a quickly converted into a string,
I could pass it into the stir function.
You might come across an error that looks something like this.
Let's say I wanted to print out, you know, today is the, and then I want to say, you know,
it's the 30th side-put-30, and I'll get an error type error.
So as you can only concatenate the string, not in, right?
So if you want to concatenate these two strings, you could wrap this number in that
stir call, and that error will go away.
Okay, so if I check the type of stir 100, we know that it's stir.
If I check the type, if I pass the string into, into here, well, we know that it would
be an end, again, if I pass the string to end, it'll come back with the integer.
You can also do this for floating point numbers, and that'll come back with the floating
point number.
Now converting between less than strings, as I mentioned, in introduction, to Python,
a string is actually just kind of considered a list or a sequence of characters.
So converting back and forth is pretty easy.
Let's say I had a variable here called greeting, and the value is hello.
I can pass that greeting into a list.
What will I see?
What will the type of this be?
It'll be a list, and how many items will it have in it?
Five items, that's right, so easy peasy.
Let's say I wanted to undo what I just did.
How do I take a list of characters and submission back into one string?
Join, yes, there's no smush method.
It's just join, okay, so if I wanted to separate these values back or combine them back
and separate them by commas, I could call join.
If I didn't make a variable for that list that I just made, I can pass the whole thing
into the string method.
I can say that my characters were a list of my greeting, so that's just kind of the same
thing.
If I wanted to combine all these characters back without a diameter, I could just join
on the empty string, and that gets us back to where we started.
To split up values and a string and a comma separated value list, like you might see,
we would say like CSV row is equal to a quick round box, and what method would we need
to call to make this a list of items?
Oh, not quite right, yeah, I will need to call split.
So with split, we call it on the list that's the string that we're taking action on,
but with join, what do we call the join method on?
The string, which string?
The delimiter string, that's exactly right, so it's kind of stuff all makes sense.
There's one other, I'll come back to it, I'll cover it later, but I showed you yesterday
how, if you had a list with some duplicates in it, let's say I had a list of names, and
you can type out your own names here, you know, maybe we have a bob, we have some folks
in the class, so we have a jaff, and we have a metal line, but then we have another
name, all right, so whichever list you make, just insert a duplicate.
If I wanted to quickly deduplicate this list of names, what data structure could I use?
Yes.
A set, right, a set cannot contain duplicates, so just like I was converting between the
other types, I can say set, pass in my list of names, now the duplicates are gone.
If I wanted to, I can convert this back into a list, you know, if I wanted to sort it,
I could pass the set into the sorted method, what comes back from sorted, what type?
It's a list, right, because lists have order sets do not, okay, so super easy to convert
back and forth, this will be really handy as you go through your Python journey.